(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)
ダメ 無理！ 変身できない！
It's not working! I can't transform!
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)両名を牢獄島において
無期の刑に処する｡
Imprison both in the prison tower,
where they will be held indefinitely.
えっ!? 無期？
What? Indefinitely?
ジャンヌ･ダルクさんは
いい人ですね｡
You're a good person, Ms. D'Arc.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ジャンヌでいい｡
はい ジャンヌさん！
Jeanne is fine.
Okay, Ms. Jeanne.
じゃあ ムガロちゃんは？
Then what about Mugaro?
おとなしくて
不思議な力を持ってる女の子｡
She's a quiet girl with a mysterious power.
その子は 男の子ではなかったか？
女の子ですよ｡
Was the child not a boy?
No, she is a girl.
女の子ですよね？
She was a girl, right?
私は ここから出る｡
うん｡ ここから出て➡
I am going to leave this place.
Let's get out of here
and go see Mugaro together.
一緒に ムガロちゃんに
会いに行きましょう！
Break time!
休憩！
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)今だ｡
うん｡
Now.
これだ｡
There it is.
よっと｡ んっ… うっ！
どうした？
What is it?
≫あっ ジャンヌさん 入れました｡
Jeanne, I'm in.
You there.
(看守)
おい お前！ 何をしている？
What are you doing?
なぜ ここにいる？
Why are you here?
申し訳ありません｡
作業に没頭して➡
My apologies.
I lost track of time
and did not hear you call for break.
休憩の合図を
聞き逃しておりました｡
間もなく休憩が終わる｡
作業に戻れ｡
Your break is ending soon.
Get back to work.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)すいません｡
I am sorry.
What an annoying prisoner.
まったく 忌々しい囚人が…｡
Damn it! She's escaping!
くそっ 脱走だ！
Come, El.
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)来なさい エル｡➡
怖がることはありません｡
You have nothing to fear.
We will set free the divine power
sleeping inside you.
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)あなたに眠る神の力
それを 全て解放するのです｡
Do you not wish to see your mother?
あなたの母に
会いたくはないですか？➡
あなたの母を
人間たちから救い出し➡
Somewhere within you,
you have the power to save your mother
from the humans
共に生きることをなす力が➡
and resume life together with her.
あなたには
秘められているのです｡➡
それだけではありません｡➡
But that is not all.
あなたの力は
この不安定な世界に➡
Your power
has the ability to bring back peace
to this unstable world.
平和を取り戻すことすら
可能なのです｡
母と 穏やかで静かなときを
過ごすために➡
In order for you to live a quiet
life with your mother,
あなたは あなたの力で
この世の救世主となるのです｡
you must use your power
to become this world's savior.
How do you feel, El?
気分はどうですか？ エル｡
I will take back my mother.
(ｴﾙ)お母さんを取り戻す｡
あっ なんです？ それ｡
What is that?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)この地下牢の地図だ｡➡
It is a map of this dungeon.
ここに入れられてから
少しずつ描き足してきた｡
I have been adding to it
since the day I was put in here.
へえ～ ジャンヌさんって
絵が上手なんですね｡
You're such a good drawer, Jeanne.
そんなことより よく見るんだ｡➡
More importantly, study it carefully.
今 私たちがいるのは ここだ｡➡
This is where we are now.
ここから脱獄するには➡
In order to escape,
first we must head for this spot here.
私たちは まず
ここを目指さなければならない｡➡
地上へと上がる手段は
この装置を使うしかない｡➡
Our only hope for reaching the surface
lies with us using this device.
脱獄するための最大の難関は
ここだ｡
This will be the most difficult challenge
for our escape.
私がやっつけます｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)おっ…｡➡
I will take them out.
警備の兵士をか？
いくら そなたでも無理だろう｡
The military guards?
Even you could not take them all on.
I'll let you in on something,
since you're a good person, Jeanne.
ジャンヌさんは
いい人だから教えてあげます｡
実は私…｡ んっ！
I can actually--
≪ピィーッ！ ピィーッ！
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)行くぞ｡
Let's go.
How did you get up here, young lady?
お嬢ちゃん どうやって入った？
Where are your parents?
どこの子だい？ 迷子なら…｡
If you're lost...
バキッ！
あっ！
ドォーン！
(一同)うわぁ～！
ごほっ ごほっ ごほっ｡
Emergency! We have an intruder!
緊急事態発生！ 侵入者だ！
≫(兵士)いたぞ！
≫シュン シュン…(矢を放つ音)
Over there!
コン！
(ﾘﾀ)あっ！
Rage of Bahamut
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)さっき 何を
言おうとしたんだ？
What were you about to say earlier?
ああ～ あれですか｡
Oh, that?
I was about to tell you my secret.
私の秘密を
教えようと思ったんです｡
Secret?
秘密？
実は私 竜になれるんです｡
I can actually transform into a dragon.
ん？ どうやってだ？
How?
It happens when I get close to a man
男の人に近づいて 心臓が
バッコン バッコンってなると…｡
and my heart starts pounding.
誠か？
私 竜族なんです｡
Is this really true?
I'm dragonfolk.
それが本当だとして
男なら誰でもいいのか？
If that is true,
could it be any man?
カイザルさんなら いけます｡
It would work with Kaisar.
う～ん… たぶん｡
Probably.
Unfortunately, the male prison
is on the other side of the device.
残念だが
男子牢は 装置を挟んで反対側だ｡
行くには 結局
警備を突破しなければならない｡
We would have to go through
the guards to reach it.
If only there was another path...
他に道があればいいが
今は分からない｡
But I do not know of any.
I see.
そうなんですか…｡
装置にたどりつけても➡
Even if we reach the device,
あの警備をどうにかしなければ…｡
あっ！
we still need to do something
about the guards.
What is it?
どうした？
見てください ジャンヌさん｡
Look, Jeanne.
It's a cute little spider.
かわいいクモがいますよ｡
(小声で)
ふぅ…｡ ちょっと ジャンヌさん➡
Jeanne.
What are you thinking,
trying to scream like that?
何 大声出そうと
しちゃってるんですか｡
(小声で)すまない｡
私は クモが苦手なんだ｡
My apologies.
I am afraid of spiders.
(考古学者)
完成には まだ時間がかかると➡
I have been telling you that
we still need time to complete it.
言っているではありませんか｡
(隊長)急げ｡➡
Hurry. It will not be long
before His Highness will require it.
陛下が示すときは
もう間もなくだ｡
(考古学者)簡単におっしゃる…｡
-You speak as if the task is simple.
-What is that king up to?
あの王様
何をたくらんでるのかしら？
(考古学者)作業に取りかかれ！
グッ！ ウッ ウゥ…
Go get him!
(ﾌﾞｴﾙ)ふふっ｡
グオォ…➡
ウオォー！
ザシュ！
Yeah!
Demon Buer.
(側近)
悪魔ブエル その戦闘力を認め➡
We acknowledge your skill in battle,
悪魔部隊の隊長に任命する｡
and hereby appoint you
captain of the Demon Division.
(一同)おおっ…｡
(観客)なんだよ？
(観客)なんだ？ これ｡
Sinful king of man,
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)罪深き 人の王よ
我ら神の命を聞きなさい｡
heed your gods.
We request the swift return
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)
これまでに 我らの神殿を襲い➡
of all you have stolen in your attacks
on our holy temples.
奪った全てのものの
速やかな返却を要求します｡➡
Furthermore, you are to release saint
Jeanne D'Arc to our custody at once.
併せて 聖女ジャンヌ･ダルクを
直ちに解放し➡
我々に引き渡しなさい｡
ここで御託を並べるより
力ずくで奪ってみたらどうだ｡
Instead of making grand proclamations,
why don't you try to take it by force?
(一同)そうだ そうだ！
-Stand down, Sofiel.
-Yes, My Lady.
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)やめなさい ソフィエル｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)はっ｡
If you will not comply,
命に背くなら
しかたありませんね｡
I suppose we have no other choice.
We will do as you say,
あなたがおっしゃるとおり➡
and take back what is ours by force.
力ずくで
取り返すことにしましょう｡
Just because you have the saint's child,
do not get carried away.
聖女の子供を手に入れたぐらいで
あまり調子に乗ると➡
It will only hasten your deaths.
死に急ぐことになるぞ｡
Death is what the gods shall bestow unto man.
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)
死は 神から人へ与えましょう｡
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ](一同)そうだ そうだ！
Do you understand now just how foolish
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)
今の人間が いかに愚かな存在か➡
mankind has become?
分かりましたか？➡
The tyrant Charioce XVII has changed mankind,
暴君シャリオス１７世によって
人は変わり➡
世は不安定な状態に陥りました｡➡
propelling the world into instability.
He is also the same man
who is keeping your mother prisoner.
そして
あなたの母を捕らえているのも➡
あの男です｡
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)あなたの力で
道を誤った人間たちを正し➡
You must use your powers
to correct humanity's path
そして 母を助け出すのです｡
and save your mother.
人を正して
お母さんを取り戻す…｡
I will correct mankind and take back my mother.
Yes.
そうです｡
それが 僕の使命…｡
That is my duty.
そうです｡
Yes, that is right.
今度は 神様と戦争だってな｡
Apparently we're going to war with the gods now.
(肉屋の妻)
ほんと 戦好きな王様だね｡
Our king sure likes to fight.
少しは 避難する方の身も
考えてほしいよ｡
I wish he would think about the ones
who have to evacuate.
(肉屋の主人)バババ… バカ！
めったなこと言うんじゃねぇよ！
Are you stupid!
Don't say anything like that out loud.
バリン！
神と戦うな！
Don't fight the gods.
(市民)王は
神より強奪したものを返却しろ！
The king should return what he stole from the gods.
ジャンヌ様を解放しろ！
Free Lady Jeanne.
(一同)ジャンヌ様を解放しろ！
Can you believe them?
(肉屋の主人)
ヤツらも よくやるよなぁ｡
They've got courage, stirring things up like that.
あんな所で大騒ぎするなんて
勇気あるねぇ｡
(市民)てやっ！
あぁ～｡
なんだか王都も変わっちまったな｡
The capital has changed.
It didn't used to be so dangerous.
こんな物騒になるなんて｡
ニーナは無事だといいが｡
I hope Nina is okay.
I hope she's not crying in her cell.
牢屋で泣いてないといいけど｡
I guess even you have things
you're scared of, Jeanne.
ジャンヌさんにも
苦手なものがあるんですね｡
Everyone has something they are afraid of.
誰にでも
苦手なものくらいあるだろう｡
なんか安心しました｡
ジャンヌさんも女の子なんですね｡
That's a relief.
I guess you're just a girl like the rest of us.
That is enough idle chatter.
無駄口は ここまでだ｡➡
The device is over there.
あそこが装置だ｡
こっから どうしましょ？
What should we do now?
There's only one option left.
残る作戦は１つ｡ 強行突破ですね｡
Forcing our way through.
No. It is too dangerous.
ダメだ！ 危険すぎる｡
でも 他に方法ないでしょ？
But there's no other way.
大丈夫です｡ 私 強いですから｡
Don't worry.
I'm strong.
うりゃあ～！ はあっ！
(兵士)うっ！
はあっ！
ん？ 襲撃だ！
We're being attacked.
ジャンヌさん！
(兵士たち)うわっ！
Jeanne!
Almost.
惜しかったな｡
脱獄ごっこは終わりだ｡
But playtime is over.
You've saved me the trouble
of walking to your cell.
牢に行く手間が省けたな｡
What business do you have with me?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)なんの用でしょうか？
The gods have declared war.
神が宣戦布告した｡
あっ…｡
If they attack us,
ヤツらが攻めてくるのなら➡
余は 容赦なく たたき潰す｡
I will crush them without mercy.
The gods will likely use your child in this war.
神は この戦争に
お前の子供を利用するだろう｡
くっ…｡
戦えば お前の子供も死ぬ｡
If your child joins them, he will die as well.
これが最後のチャンスだ｡
余に下れ｡
This is your final chance.
Pledge your fealty to me.
Persuade your son, and prevent this war.
息子を説得し 戦を回避しろ｡
You are the only one who can do this.
貴様にだけ できることだ｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)
なぜ今更 そんなことを私に？
Why ask this of me now
after everything you've done?
以前と変わらず いまだ
神を信仰する人間たちがいる｡
There are still those who follow the gods.
元聖女としてのお前が余に付けば
ヤツらの幻想に➡
If a former saint like you
would pledge yourself to me,
then we would be able to put an end
to their delusions.
ﾋﾟﾘｵﾄﾞを打つことができるだろう｡
(兵士)うわっ…｡
どうだ？
神も お前の息子も死なず➡
What say you?
Neither the gods nor your son will have to die,
and needless blood will not be spilled.
無駄な血が流れない｡
What guarantee do I have
that you will keep your promise?
その約束が果たされる保証は？
There are a number of lives that can be saved
by your choice.
お前の選択で
いくつもの救われる命がある…➡
と言っている｡
くっ…｡
That is what I am saying.
さあ どうする？
Now, what is your decision?
やめろ！
ジャンヌさんをいじめるな！
Stop it. Don't pick on Jeanne.
Why do you always pick on people?
なんで
お前は いつも いじめるんだ！
そんなことして 何が楽しいんだ！
What's so fun about that?
What do you want?
なんだよ？ うっ…｡
牢獄生活は楽しいか？
Are you enjoying prison life?
た… 楽しいわけないだろ！
だから脱獄したのか？
Of course I'm not!
Is that why you're fleeing?
うっ… 別に｡
No...
グゥ～…(おなかの音)
あっ｡
変わらないな お前は｡
You haven't changed.
何！ なんなのよ！
What? What do you know!
また踊ってくれるか？
はっ…｡
Would you dance with me again?
あっ いや…｡
I can't believe it.
そ… そんな…｡
How can it...
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)
陛下 私は あなたには従いません｡
Your Highness.
I will not be following you.
神を…
私を信じる民を裏切ることなど➡
I cannot betray the gods,
nor the people who believe in me.
到底できることではありません｡
I see. Then I have no other choice.
そうか｡ ならば しかたがないな｡
神と子が滅ぶのを➡
You can return to your cell and wait
as your child and your precious gods
march to the slaughter.
牢に戻り じっと待つがいい｡
It's okay, it's okay
I cast the usual spell
≫ドサッ ドサッ！
えっ？ な… 何!?
Stagnation, stagnation
My words and heart are at odds
Default
I've taken all the paint
And mixed up all the colors
Until you're left with me
リタ～！
ふぅ…｡
ふふん｡
So fragile
Yet strong
Close to overflowing
But not spilling
Because I'm incomplete
I won't amount to much
This is just a good luck charm
I'm not asking for your help
I was just clinging to you
Let's end it all today
I'm done living this pointless life
I've taken my last, pointless breath
To whom it may concern, see ya and goodbye
I killed the person I was yesterday
A new morning is coming
What was that?
Rita!
- Favaro!
- What is it!? Why are you so close!
I'm just so happy to see you again!
What the hell?
Next time on Rage of Bahamut:
Virgin Soul, "The Great Escape."
- Have you always been like this?
- Is it that noticeable?
BAHA SOUL!!
Baha Baha Baha Soul.
You'll watch next time too, right?